Shawe-Taylor mss., 1929-1995 LMC 1954
Lilly Library
- Writings
  - Scripts. (Box 3)
    - Voice and Style. For BBC Third Programme. Four talks, Feb. 1953; (1 folder) (Box 3)
      - 4. Three Lieder Singers., carbon typescript, 7 p. (Box 3)
    - Die Walküre and Its Interpreters., carbon typescript, 4 p. (Box 3)
    - Walton's Operas. For Music Magazine, Mar. 26, 1972; photocopy, 4 p. (Box 3)
    - War and Peace., mimeograph, 9 p. (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous notes. (Box 3)
  - Notebooks (Box 3)
    - 1. Brief critiques of recordings and live performances (Box 3)
    - 2. Lists of recordings, operas and opera singers. (Box 3)
  - Writings by others (Box 3)
    Mostly mimeograph articles, but also includes: Uncorrected copy of Hans Werner Henze's We Come to the River; interview with Sir Edward Downes about the Australian Opera
- Financial/legal
  - E.S. Cope estate. (Box 3)
    Chiefly correspondence with lawyers and relatives concerning the settlement of estate.
  - Insurance. (Box 3)
    Property, vehicle and home insurance policies and related correspondence
  - Lloyd's Bank. Statements, 1935-1988; (4 folders) (Box 3)
  - Lloyd's Bank (cont.)., (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Rathbone. Correspondence with "Rathbone Bros. & Co. (investors)", 1942-1995; (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - Statements of investments, 1940-1995; (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous financial materials. (Box 4)
- Photographs (Box 4)
  - Shawe-Taylor, Desmond., 16 photographs, including one snapshot. (Box 4)
    see also: Snapshots
  - Shawe-Taylor, Fannie (Mrs. Wm. C. Trench). Shawe-Taylor's aunt, holding tennis racket, ca. 1890 (Box 4)
  - Military., 35 snapshots of unidentified men in military uniforms (Box 4)
  - Singers., 19 photographs of various operatic singers, mostly in costume. Includes seven portraits of Emma Eames (Box 4)
  - Snapshots., 99 photographs, mostly of friends. A few include Shawe-Taylor. (2 folders) (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Historic Masters Ltd., 1984-1995; (Issues 78rpm records in their original form.) 2 folders (Box 4)
    Shawe-Taylor was on the Board of Directors. Contains correspondence, minutes of board and general meetings and financial accounts. Arranged chronologically.
  - Oxford. (Box 4)
    Programs and menus from Shawe-Taylor's college years at Oxford University.
  - Personal. (Box 4)
    Materials unrelated to Shawe-Taylor's writing career, such as receipts concerning utilities, membership in The Wine Society, BUPA, etc.
  - Postcards., 75 postcards, chiefly depicting scenery. (Box 4)
  - Press releases. English National Opera, Glyndebourne Festival Opera, The Royal Opera, and The Welsh National Opera (Box 4)
  - Programs., Chiefly music programs (Box 4)
  - Record catalogs. Includes catalogs from: Collector's Corner, The Complete Record Company, EMI, Harmonia Mundi, and many other record selling companies, (5 folders) (Box 4)
  - Record catalogs (cont.), (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Travel., Notes, maps, brochures, notebook of contacts in the U.S. and Mexico for trips to Iran, U.S., Australia and Europe. (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Miscellany., (2 folders) (Box 5)
- Clippings (Box 5)
  - Articles written by Shawe-Taylor, 1930-1966; (4 folders) (Box 5)
  - Letters to editors, or articles about Shawe-Taylor., (1 folder) (Box 5)
  - Articles by and about others, (4 folders) (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook of articles by Edward Sackville-West (Box 5)